Guide to the Phil and Maddy Handler papers,1963-2013.
Handler, Phil and Maddy papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Phil and Maddy Handler papers, 1963-2013.
41-5-3229
Philip S.(Philip Stephan), Handler 1940-
1 cubic ft.
Clippings, catalogs, articles, reminiscences, and other source materials for the videos
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files relating to research and DVD versions of videos created by Fly on the Wall Productions.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Phil Handler, Cornell University B.Arch. 1964, M.Arch. 1965 and Maddy Handler, B.S. 1965 created videotapes documenting the experiences of Cornell Architecture alumni. They own and run Fly on the Wall Productions, which documents construction projects using video and digital photography.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
DVD versions of videos created by Fly on the Wall Productions: "Cornell University Reunion 2000: AA&P Catalyst for Creativity," with Bruce Abbey, Peter Barton, Tad Mann, Blue Minges, Dell Mitchell, Brad Perkins, Joel Perlman, Peter Rosen, Alan Saret, Warren Schwartz, and Jon Stoumen; "Millennium Box Dedication," 2000; "Cornell University Reunion 2001: AA&P Catalyst for Creativity," with Bob Matyas, Jack Dollard, Stuart Carter, and Bob Jawitz; "Video Vignettes of the AA&P Class of '62 Reunion 2002" and "Cornell University Reunion 2002: AA&P Class of '62 Symposium."
Also, "Cornell University Council: Fifty Years & Counting, October 25-28, 2000."
Clippings, catalogs, articles, reminiscences, and other source materials for the videos.
Reunion 2003: "Video Vignettes of Cornell AA&P Class of 1963" including Marjorie Walker Sayer, Madeleine Leston Meehan, Donna Forsman, Peter Parsons, Tom Beeby, Bob Fox, and Alan Chimacoff, and "Elsie Dinsmore Popkin: A Profile for Cornell Views Through the Seasons," exhibit at the Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art, June 4,-July 6, 2003 (2 DVDs).
Reunion 2004: "Video Vignettes of Cornell AA&P Class of 1964" including Jack C. Dobson, Leslie Checkley Morse-Goldfarb, Ortrude Busse White, Valerie Jesraly Seligsohn, Paul W. Fox, and Linda Brandt Myers. Also, "Being Eisenman: A Video about Peter Eisenman, Cornell Class of '54 Architecture '55"; "Eisenman: Being Back: Remarks by Peter Eisenman at the AA&P Dean's Breakfast, June 12, 2004"; and "The Architect's Work I Peter Eisenman" exhibit brochure, 2004 (3 DVDs).
"True Big Red: The life & work of Don Greenberg, '55"; and "Journey from Sibley: Jill Lerner '75 B Arch 76," both 2005 (DVDs).
"Big Red/Meier White: A Cornell Story," a video about Richard A. Meier, Cornell Class of '56, Architecture '57, produced in honor of his 50th Reunion, June, 2006 (DVD). Also, folder of documentation for the project.
"Welcoming the Popkin Pastel," Statler Hotel, Cornell University, April 1, 2006 (DVD).
"Simply Squier," 2007, DVD in honor of Professor Emeritus Jack Squier, MFA '52 & Jane Squier. Also, research files and publicity for the project. DVD version of 1963 slide show by Randy Lewis: "The Plantations Sculpture Project," February-May 1963, showing the construction of a sculpture at the Cornell Plantations by Alan Chimacoff, Randy Lewis, and Webb Nichols, under the supervision of Professor Squier, with slides by Lewis and Chimacoff.
"Portrait of a Cornell Artist: Elsie Dinsmore Popkin '58," 2008
"Ratan Tata '59: The Cornell Story, on his 50th Reunion, June 4, 2009." "Celebrating Yervant: Looking Back at 70," video about Yervant Terzian, the David C. Duncan Professor in the Physical Sciences, Department of Astronomy, 2009.
"Voices of 1965: Cornell Reunion Event, June 10-12, 2010."
"A Century at Llenroc," 2011 DVD.
"Jack Squier Day at Cornell," 2007 DVD.
"Remembering Our Days on the Hill: Cornell Class of 1962 50th Reunion, June 7-10, 2012," featuring George Telesh, Mike Duesing, Jane Brody, Clark Halstead, Char Jones Collister, Sam Fleming, Jan McClayton Crites, Alex Steinbergh, and Harry Edwards (DVD).
"Cornell AA&P 125th Anniversary, October 4 & 5, 1996: Part 1 Disc 1 Henry Cobb, Richard Meier & Frank Stella; Disk 2 Ann Markusen; Part 2 Disc 3 Arthur Danto; Disc 4 Herbert Muschamp; Interviews. Colin Rowe Festschrift, April 28, 1996, Part 1 and 2.
Clippings, catalogs, articles, reminiscences, and other source materials for the videos.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Handler, Philip S.1940-; Abbey, Bruce James.; Barton, Peter.; Beeby, Tom.; Carter, Stuart Lee.; Cobas, Jaime.; Chimacoff, Alan.; Dobson, Jack C.; Dollard, Jack.; Eisenman, Peter, 1932-; Forsman, Donna.; Fox, Bob.; Fox, Paul W.; Greenberg, Donald P.(Donald Peter), 1934-; Handler, Maddy Gell.; Halstead, Clark.; Hebald, Margo.; Hoffman, Larry.; Jawitz, Robert.; Kaufman, Harvey.; Lerner, Jill.; Lewis, Randy.; Mann, A. T., 1943-; Matzkin, Arlene Hutton; Matzkin, Don; Matyas, Robert.; Meehan, Madeleine Leston.; Meier, Richard, 1934-; Minges, Blue.; Mitchell, Dell Worn.; Morse-Goldfarb, Leslie Checkley.; Myers, Linda Brandt.; Nichols, Webb.; Parsons, Peter.; Perkins, Bradford.; Perlman, Joel, 1943-; Popkin, Elsie Dinsmore, 1937-2005.; Rosen, Peter.; Saret, Alan, 1944-; Schumacher, Tom, 1941-2009; Sayer, Marjorie Walker.; Schwartz, Warren.; Seligsohn, Valerie Jesraly.; Squier, Jack.; Squier, Jane.; Stoumen, Jon.; Tata, Ratan.; Terzian, Yervant, 1939-; White, Ortrude Busse.; Cornell Plantations.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University--Anniversaries, etc.; Cornell University.College of Architecture, Art, and Planning.; Cornell University.Class of 1951.; Cornell University.Class of 1954.; Cornell University.Class of 1955.; Cornell University.Class of 1956.; Cornell University.Class of 1958.; Cornell University.Class of 1959.; Cornell University.Class of 1961.; Cornell University.Class of 1962.; Cornell University.Class of 1963.; Cornell University.Class of 1964.; Cornell University.Class of 1965.; Cornell University.Class of 1966.; Cornell University.Class of 1975.; Cornell University.Council.; Fly on the Wall Productions.
Subjects:
Architecture--Study and teaching.; Architects.; Scupltors, American; Class reunions.; Cornell University--Fraternities.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Jaime Cobas (Box 1, Folder 1)
- I. M. Pei (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Joel Perlman (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Peter Rosen (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Alan Saret (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Source Material Year I (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cornell: Catalyst for Creativity - Source Material Year II (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Source Material Year III (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Source Material Year IV (Box 1, Folder 9)
- AA&P Reunion 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Class of 1962 Alumni Exhibition (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Leslie Checkley Morse Goldfarb (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Valerie Seligsohn (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cornell Chronicle Article - Commencement 2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Reunion 2004 Highlights (Box 1, Folder 15)
- The Architect's Work I - Peter Eisenman (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cornell University Council Fifty Years & Counting, 2000; DVD 1 (Box 2)
- True Big Red - The life and work of Don Greenberg '55, 2005; DVD 22 (Box 2)
- Journey From Sibley - Jill Lerner '75, B Arch 76, 2005; DVD 23 (Box 2)
- Cornell University Reunion 2000 AA&P Catalyst for Creativity, DVD 31 (Box 2)
- Cornell University Reunion 2001 AA&P Catalyst for Creativity, DVD 32 (Box 2)
- Cornell University Reunion 2002 AA&P Class of '62 Symposium, DVD 33 (Box 2)
- Video Vignettes of the AA&P Class of '62 Reunion 2002, DVD 34 (Box 2)
- Video Vignettes of Cornell AA&P Class of '64 Reunion 2004, DVD 35 (Box 2)
- Being Eisenman. Peter Eisenman, 2004; DVD 36 (Box 2)
- Eisenman: Being Back, 2004; DVD 37 (Box 2)
- Elsie Dinsmore Popkin. A Profile for Cornell Views Through the Seasons., 2003; DVD 38 (Box 2)
- Video Vignettes of Cornell AA&P Class of '63 Reunion, 2003, DVD 39 (Box 2)
- Big Red / Meier White, A Cornell Story. Richard A. Meier (2 copies), 2006; DVD 40 (Box 2)
- Welcoming the Popkin Pastel, 2006; DVD 61 (Box 2)
- Cornell Plantations, Chimacoff, Lewis, Nichols, 1963; DVD 198 (Box 2)
- Simply Squier. Jack Squier and Jane Squier, 2007; DVD 199 (Box 2)
- Cornell University Millennium Box Dedication, 2000; DVD 200 (Box 2)
- Portrait of a Cornell Artist. Elsie Dinsmore Popkin, 2008; DVD 502 (Box 2)
- Ratan Tata, 2009; DVD 675-676 (Box 2)
- Celebrating Yervant. Looking Back at 70, Yervant Terzian., 2009; DVD 677 (Box 2)
- Voices of 1965, 2010; DVD 687 (Box 2)
- A Century at Llenroc, 2011; DVD 720 (Box 2)
- Jack Squier Day at Cornell, 2007; DVD 796 (Box 2)
- Remembering Our Days on the Hill, Cornell Class of 1962, 50th reunion, 2012; DVD 801 (Box 2)
- Colin Rowe Festschrift, Part 1 and 2, 1996; DVD 916-917 (Box 2)
- Cornell AA&P 125th Anniversary, Disc 1 and 2, 1996; DVD 918-919 (Box 2)
- Cornell AA&P 125th Anniversary, Disc 3 and 4, 1996; DVD 920-921 (Box 2)
- Colin Rowe Memorial Program, The Carnegie Institution of Washington, DC, February 6, 2000, DVD 1172 (Box 2)
- Colin by Colin, Presented at the Memorial Celebration in His Honor, February 6, 2000, DVD 1173 (Box 2)
- Richard Meier Project, 1963, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Squier Project publicity, 2005, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Simply Squier Project, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Copies of clippings from The Cornell Engineer and N.Y. Times, 1957, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Copies of Zeta Beta Tau photos, 1954, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Tata Review, 2013; Loose (Box 3)